greens.org.nz 2018-12-23

# Privacy Policy | Green Party of Aotearoa New Zealand

The Green Party takes your privacy seriously and we take care to keep information you submit to this website secure. We do not share your personal information with other organisations, unless required to by law or specified  in this privacy policy.

Note, however, we reserve the right to alter this privacy policy at any time without notice.

**Providing information is optional.**

You do NOT have to supply information to us.

However, if you choose not to provide information, such as your name, email address, and phone number you are unable:

  * to subscribe to our email newsletter, sign an online petition, or sign up as a volunteer.
  * to donate to the Party online.
  * to join the Party as a member.
  * to purchase items from the online store.

Joining as a member, subscribing to email newsletters, signing our online petitions, signing up as a volunteer or contacting us, does mean you agree to receive communications from us.

### **Why might we collect your information?**

We collect personal information to:

  * keep in touch with you, including by email, post, phone, and text message;
  * campaign, market, and tailor communications to you;
  * manage membership, volunteering, and donations;
  * accurately declare the number of Party members to the Electoral Commission;
  * process store purchases;
  * run the members’ website, discussion forums, and groups;
  * monitor and improve our website and systems; and
  * comply with legal requirements including those related to Party membership, donations, and loans.

### **What information might we collect?**

We may collect personal information provided voluntarily by you, including your:

  * Name and contact information,
  * Green Party username(s) and password(s),
  * billing and purchase information,
  * policy interests,
  * demographic information,
  * interactions with us,
  * location,
  * computer or network information. 
  * if you interact with Party or Green Member of Parliament accounts on social media such as Facebook and Twitter, we may collect personal information such as your name, social media account name.

Although we use cookies on our web sites, no personally identifiable information is associated with them unless you log in.

We may match information collected with information from other sources, including public sources such as the electoral roll.

We may use third-party tools (such as Google Analytics), log files, and cookies to collect statistical and demographic information about website visitors, including location, browser details, behavioural and interaction information (including referral URLs and search terms), and computer and network information. Google provides instructions to opt-out of having information collected by Google Analytics: <https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/181881>.

### **Contacting us**

You have the right to ask for a copy of any personal information we hold about you, and to ask for it to be corrected if you think it is wrong.

If you would like to ask for a copy of your information, or to have it corrected, please email to [generalsecretary@greens.org.nz](mailto:generalsecretary@greens.org.nz) or contact us on 04 801 5102, or PO Box 11652, Manners Street, Wellington 6142.

You may unsubscribe from our mailing lists by following the unsubscribe instructions at the bottom of our emails, or replying ‘STOP’ to a text message sent by us. You can update some preferences and information yourself by logging in to our website.

If you have any queries about this website, please email [greenparty@greens.org.nz](mailto:greenparty@greens.org.nz).

### **Do we share this information?**

No, we do not.  Personal information held by the Green Party will never be passed on to third parties, unless required by law or as specified in this privacy policy.

Where this information is required for them to carry out their duties, we might share some information with staff, contractors, volunteers, candidates, Members of Parliament (and their staff), and officeholders.

We share some information with suppliers of services to the Party, which may be collected, stored and processed on servers located outside of New Zealand. Online credit card payments are encrypted, processed using an external credit card payment processor (for example, Flo2cash), and credit card numbers are not stored by us.

If you sign a petition, open letter, make a submission or something similar we may share your name with the relevant decision maker (e.g. Parliament).

We may share anonymised versions of your data with partners like social media providers to help achieve our goals by delivering personalised social media content to current and potential supporters.

To help our supporters draw their friends’ attention to the issues they care about, we provide social media sharing buttons and widgets on our website. These buttons or widgets may track your behaviour on our website and may combine this with other information about your online behaviour from other websites.

We may disclose information when we believe it is appropriate to comply with the law, facilitate legal proceedings, prevent harm to people or property in an emergency, or protect our rights.

### **Our legal obligations**

The Party is a registered incorporated society, and we are required under the Incorporated Societies Act 1908 to keep a register of members’ names, addresses, and joining date. This register must be provided to the Registrar upon request.

We are required to keep and disclose certain financial information for accounting, tax, and audit purposes, including under the Goods and Services Tax Act 1985, Income Tax Act 2007, and Tax Administration Act 1994.

As a registered political party, we are required under the Electoral Act 1993 to collect and disclose certain records, including those related to donations, expenses, loans, and membership.

### **Donations**

It is our policy to ask for donations to support the running of the party and campaign work.  Occasionally we ask for donations for a specific action.  Very occasionally, it is not possible to use your donation for that specific action, in which case we would put the donation in our general funds to support our wider work.  If for any reason you are not happy for your donation to be used in this way, we will of course refund it.  You can email [fundraising@greens.org.nz](mailto:fundraising@greens.org.nz) for a refund.

Donations to political parties are not tax deductible in New Zealand.

### **Donations Disclosures**

The secretary of each registered political party must file an annual return of party donations and loans with the Electoral Commission by 30 April of the following year for donations and loans received in the last 12 months, for the year ending 31 December.

Providing you are a New Zealand citizen or otherwise legally registered as an NZ elector, or an organisation or company registered in New Zealand, you can donate as much as you would like to a political party.

Certain records, including large donors’ names and addresses, must be published by the Electoral Commission on their website:

  * If you donate more than $15,000 in a calendar year we are required by law to disclose your name and address and the amount you have donated in our annual return to the Electoral Commission. The information is published on the Commission’s website.
  * If you donate more than $30,000 in a 12-month period then we are also required by law to make an immediate disclosure (within 10 working days) to the Electoral Commission. The information is immediately published on the Commission’s website.

There are restrictions on anonymous donations and donations by non-New Zealanders or companies not resident in New Zealand:

  * We are unable to retain any amount over $1,500 donated by someone who chooses not to provide identifying information. Donors who wish to donate over $1,500 and remain anonymous can follow a special process set up by the Electoral Commission: <https://www.elections.org.nz/parties-candidates/registered-political-parties/party-donations-and-loans/donations-protected>
  * You can email to [generalsecretary@greens.org.nz](mailto:generalsecretary@greens.org.nz) if you would like more information.

(Last revised October 2018)
